你可以开启多个 Claude Code 会话
You can open multiple sessions with Claude
来并行开发多个功能。
Code to work on many features in parallel.
为了管理这些会话并确保不会
To manage these sessions and make sure you're not
覆盖同一个文件，你可以使用 Git worktrees。
overwriting the same file, you can use Git worktrees.
现在让我们添加 Git worktrees，同时
So let's add Git worktrees to add
为聊天机器人添加三个并行功能。
three features to the chatbot in parallel.
一会儿见。现在我准备跳回 Claude。
I'll see you there. So I'm going to hop back into Claude.
正如我们之前看到的，Claude Code 内置了
And as we saw earlier, Claude Code comes built in
相当多的斜杠命令。
with quite a few slash commands.
但你也可以创建自己的
But you can also make your
自定义命令。
own. To make your own custom commands,
在 .claude 文件夹内，
inside of the dot claude folder.
让我们新建一个名为 commands 的文件夹。
Let's make a new folder called commands.
在里面，我们将创建一个 Markdown 文件，
And inside of here, we're going to make a markdown file
文件名就是你想要的命令名。
with the name of the command that we'd like.
我要创建的命令叫作 implement feature。
The command here that I'm going to make is called implement feature.
所以我创建了一个名为 implement-feature.md 的文件。
So I'll create a markdown file called implement-feature.md
在这个文件中，你可以放入任何你想要的内容。
Inside here, I can place whatever I'd like.
但我想向你展示一个非常特别的功能：
But what I want to show you that's very special
如果你有任何参数
is if you have any arguments you
想向自定义命令传递，可以使用
want to pass to your custom command, you can reference it using
这个 $ARGUMENTS 变量来引用它。
this $ARGUMENTS variable.
我在这里的要求是：
So what I'm asking for here
当使用此命令时，
is that when this command is used,
我会指明你正在实现一个新功能。
I'll be specifying that you're implementing a new feature.
用户可以指定该功能是什么，
The user can then specify whatever that feature is,
然后我希望确保
and then I want to make
Claude Code 清楚地知道
sure that Claude Code is well aware
只针对前端功能执行此操作，
to only do this for front-end features,
并将更改写入 frontend-changes.md 文件。
and to write the changes made to a file called frontend-changes.md
你可以想象，自定义命令有很多不同的用例，
You can imagine there are many different use cases for custom commands,
比如特定的测试方式或运行文件的方式。
certain ways you want to run tests or run files.
需要注意的是，你放在这里的内容
and anything that you put in here
不会自动添加到你的上下文中，
does not automatically get added to your context,
这与 CLAUDE.md 不同。
unlike a CLAUDE.md
因此，如果你希望某些内容应用于
So if you want something to be applied
你开启的每一个 Claude Code 实例，
to every single instance of Claude Code that you make,
请使用 CLAUDE.md 文件。
use your CLAUDE.md file.
但如果你只是有一些特定的命令
But if you just have specific commands
可能在不同对话中选择性使用，
that you may or may not use across different conversations,
这里就是一个非常好的存放地。
right here is a great place to put them.
我将在开始讨论 worktrees 时
I'm going to be using this custom command
使用这个自定义命令。
when I start talking about worktrees.
但在那之前，让我们退出 Claude Code，
But before we do that, let's quit out of Claude Code,
重新进入并验证一下
hop back in and just verify
是否能看到该自定义命令。
that we can see that custom command.
瞧，我看到了 implement feature，描述
And here, I see implement feature, and I see the description
正是来自该 Markdown 文件的第一部分。
is coming from the first part of this markdown file.
既然我已经添加了这个自定义命令，
Now that I've added this custom command,
让我们把它添加并提交。
let's go ahead and add and commit it.
我可以在命令行中执行此操作，
I could do this from the command line,
但我打算让 Claude 帮我完成。
but I'm actually going to ask Claude to do that for me.
添加并提交已做的更改。
Add and commit changes made.
这样很好，因为 Claude Code 可以生成
This is nice so that Claude Code can create
一个精练的提交消息
a nice commit message
并附带已完成工作的描述性信息。
with some descriptive information for what was done.
我们将看到它正在添加 .claude 文件夹
We'll see that it's adding the .claude folder
并执行必要的提交命令。
and committing with the commands necessary.
我们可以看到这已添加到存储库中。
We can see here that this has been added to the repository.
由于我们之前已经授予了权限，
And since we've granted permissions for this already,
所以无需再次响应确认。
we don't have to respond again.
如果你好奇这些权限信息存在哪里，
If you're ever curious where that lives,
在 .claude 文件夹内，
inside of the claude folder,
有一个 settings.local.json 文件。
there is a settings.local.json file
在这个文件中，我们可以指定
Inside of this file, we can specify
已允许的命令，这样就不需要
what commands we've allowed so that we don't need
每次都进行确认。
to confirm every single time.
同样，正如你在这里看到的，
As you can see here, as well,
当我们使用 playwright 时给予了权限。
when we use playwright, we gave permissions.
如果你想添加自己的权限，
And if you'd like to add your own,
可以轻松地在这个文件中修改，
you can easily do so in this file,
或者使用便捷的 /permissions 命令。
or even with the handy /permissions command.
现在自定义命令已经设置好了，
Now that we've got that custom command set up,
让我们聊聊如何
let's talk a little bit about how we
与 Claude Code 并行工作。
might want to work in parallel with Claude Code.
与其只是打开多个终端窗口
Instead of just opening up multiple terminal
并直接在这个代码库上操作，
windows and working directly on this code base,
我们将使用 Git 来确保
we're going to use Git to make sure
在拥有多个 Claude Code 实例时
that we don't overwrite existing files when we have
不会覆盖现有文件。
multiple instances of Claude Code.
我可能会有两个不同的
I might have two different instances of
Claude Code 实例在操作同一个文件。
Claude Code operating on the same file.
如果我在目前的
And if I do that with
环境下这样做，
the environment that I'm in right now,
会导致覆盖、产生 Bug
there's going to be overwriting, bug
以及相当大的混乱。
creation and quite a bit of confusion.
幸运的是，Git 有一个非常棒的功能
Thankfully, Git has an excellent option here
叫作 worktrees。
to use a feature called worktrees.
Worktrees 允许我基本上创建代码库副本，
And worktrees allow me to essentially create copies of the codebase,
在隔离环境中操作，
operate in isolation,
最后再将它们合并。事实上，
and then at the end, merge those in together. And in fact,
我还可以利用 Claude 来协助合并
I can use Claude to help with that merging
和管理这些 worktrees。
and management of my worktrees.
要开始使用 worktrees，
To get started with worktrees,
我首先创建一个名为 .trees 的文件夹。
I'm going to first make a folder called .trees
在这个文件夹里，
And inside of this worktrees folder,
我将添加几个 worktrees。
I'm going to go ahead and add a couple worktrees.
使用 git worktree add 命令，
Let's add a work tree using the Git worktree add command.
指定文件夹以及
and then we'll specify the folder as well
我想要的 worktree 名称。
as the name of the work tree that I want to add.
我们将第一个命名为 ui_feature，
We'll call this one ui_feature. We'll
接着再添加一个
then go ahead and add another one
叫作 testing_feature，
called testing_feature,
最后第三个叫作 quality_feature。
and then finally a third one called quality_feature.
为了确认已创建所有这些，我查看一下，
To confirm I've created all of these, I can take a look
可以看到我当前在 main 分支上，
and I can see that I'm on the main branch currently
并且创建了三个独立的 worktrees。
and that I've created three separate worktrees.
为了在这些环境中正确设置，
To set up correctly in each of these environments,
我将打开 .trees 文件夹，
I'm going to open up the trees folder,
并为每一个 worktree
and I'm going to open up
开启一个终端。
a terminal for each one of them.
我先开启 ui_feature 窗口，
I'll start with my ui_feature and bring that over here.
接着开启 testing_feature，
I'll then go ahead, bring in my testing feature,
把它放在旁边。
and I'll move that right to the side.
最后，开启我们的 quality_feature。
Finally, let's bring in our quality_feature.
把它放在上面。
Go ahead, bring that over up here.
为了腾出更多
To give us a little more
空间，我们把窗口调小一点。
room, we'll make this a bit smaller.
现在我们有了三个专用的终端窗口。
And now we have three dedicated terminal windows.
我们把资源管理器也隐藏掉。
And we'll hide the explorer as well.
现在，在每个环境中都打开 Claude。
Now, let's open up Claude for each one of these environments.
我们现在可以并行运行 Claude Code，并
What we can do now is run Claude Code in parallel and
确保修改相同文件时不会互相覆盖，
make sure that if the same files are modified, we're not overwriting
稍后合并这些
and we can fix that later
worktrees 时再进行修复。
when we merge in these worktrees.
我将使用 implement-feature 命令，
I'm going to use this implement-feature command.
然后输入
And then I'm going to put in
我想要的一个特定功能。
a particular feature that I'd like here.
该功能是：添加一个切换按钮
And that feature allows me to add a
来在深色和浅色主题之间切换。
toggle button to switch between dark and light themes.
开始创建按钮、定位，
So let's go ahead and create a toggle button, position it,
并确保可以针对该按钮进行导航。
and make sure that I can navigate for this particular toggle button.
我们从这一部分开始，
We'll start with this part and
然后再添加浅色主题变体。
then add in the light theme variant.
在它运行的同时，我可以移动到另一个工作树。
While this is running, I can now move to another work tree.
在第二个工作树中，考虑一下
And in this second work tree, let's start thinking
我想要为这个
a little bit about what I
测试框架做点什么。
want to do for this testing framework.
输入一个提示词，要求增强
going to pass in a prompt here to enhance
现有的测试框架并为 FastAPI 端点添加测试。
the existing testing framework and add additional tests for FastAPI endpoints.
在运行的同时，让我们添加一些核心的
While that's going, let's add some essential
代码质量工具到开发流程中。
code quality tools to our development workflow.
在这个过程中，我们可以开始
As we do this, we can start
看到正在请求更改。
to see that changes are being requested.
让我们在这些环境之间切换
So let's go ahead and shift between these
并确认我们
environments and confirm the changes that
想要的更改。测试正在编写中，
we want. Our tests are being written
用于分析代码库结构和
and our additional development dependencies for analyzing
格式化的额外开发依赖项也在添加。
code base structure and formatting are being added as well.
我们会看到这里
What we're going to see here
正在修改 pyproject.toml 文件。
is that we're modifying a file called pyproject.toml
还会看到有一个请求被添加进来
And we're also going to see that there's a request being added
来编辑该特定文件。
to edit that particular file as well.
随着我们继续这些操作，
As we continue these options
将对这些文件进行编辑，
will make edits to these files,
我们会看到，与此同时
and we'll go ahead and see at the same time
前端代码正按预期完成。
that our front end code is being done as expected.
我们可以并行工作并确保
We can work in parallel and make sure
这些特定的更改不会被代码库的
that none of these particular changes are being overwritten by
其他部分覆盖。如果碰巧
other parts of the codebase. If there happen
对相似的文件进行了修改，
to be changes that we've made to similar files,
我们可以确保修复合并冲突，
we can ensure that those merge conflicts are fixed.
而且可以利用 Claude 来完成。
and we can do that using Claude.
前端更改正在写入，
Our front-end changes are being written,
我们在添加更多测试，还在添加一些
we're adding more tests, and we're adding some
格式化工具和质量检查开发脚本。
formatting tools and development scripts for quality checks.
我们将按预期进行，
So we're going to proceed as expected,
确保质量脚本已完成，
making sure that quality scripts are being done,
看来前端功能正在添加。
and it looks like our front-end features are being added.
现在，添加浅色主题，
Now, add that light theme,
就像之前那样。使用自定义命令
the same way that we did previously. We'll use our implement feature,
以确保我们将其写入变更日志。
custom command to make sure we're writing that to our change log.
我们还会添加
and we'll add a light theme as
浅色主题。完成后，我们将
well. Once that's done, we'll go ahead and
准备一些其他关于 JS
cue up a few other prompts we'd like
功能和实现细节的提示词。
for JavaScript functionality and implementation details.
运行的同时，我可以检查其他脚本。
So while that's running, I can check in on other scripts.
确认我想要运行它们，
I can confirm I want to run those,
如果有问题，Claude Code 会根据需要修复。
and if there's something going on, Claude Code can fix per necessary.
似乎有一些 Claude 不知道的脚本，
Seems like there are some scripts that Claude doesn't know about,
所以我们要么安装依赖，
so we'll go ahead and either install dependencies
要么确保按预期运行。
or make sure we're running things as expected.
可以看到，我们从代码质量检查开始。
You can see here, we're starting from code quality checks.
编写了 API 端点测试，正在添加更多
We've written our API endpoint testing and we're adding more
前端功能。一旦全部
front end functionality. Once this is all
完成，我们可以前往浏览器确认。
done, we can head over to the browser.
确认检查已完成，
We can confirm our checks are done,
但在那之前，
but before we go ahead and do that,
让我们汇总所有这些独立的更改。
let's bring in all of these individual changes.
如果我们想运行测试，
If we wanted to run the tests,
我们可以确认这符合预期。
we can confirm this is as expected.
想去浏览器进行
We want to head to the browser
UI 测试也可以。
for our UI testing, we can do so.
瞧，格式化已完成，开发脚本已添加，
And here we can see Codebase formatting is done, Development scripts have
文档也已经
been added, and documentation has been
更新。我们之前看到
updated. We saw before there was a
pyproject.toml 文件在两个不同工作树中被修改。
the pyproject.toml file that was added across two different worktrees.
所以汇总这些部分时可能会有冲突。
So there might be some conflicts when figuring out these individual pieces.
既然对每一个
Now that we feel good about each
更改都感觉良好，让我们提交并附带描述性消息。
of these changes, let's add and commit with a descriptive message.
在这个工作树上也执行同样的操作。
Let's also do the same thing on this work tree.
由于我们要合并这些提交，
Since we're going to be merging in these particular commits,
我们需要清晰的提交消息
we're going to want to make sure we have descriptive commit messages
来理解每个工作区做了什么。
we can understand what was done in each of these worktrees.
我们完成了这个提交，
We've committed this particular commit,
我们在这一个上也做同样的操作。
we're doing the same on this one right here.
我们完成了 UI 增强。所以让我们也做同样的操作。
We finished up our UI enhancement. So let's do the same.
添加并提交并附带描述性消息。
add and commit with a descriptive message.
如果你发现自己经常写这种
If you find yourself writing these kinds of
提交提示词，
prompts like add and commit with a descriptive message,
这也可以是
this also could be another use case for
自定义命令的一个很好的用例，
a nice custom command where we can specify
我们可以指定想要的消息风格
exactly some styling that we want or the
或公司的 Git 最佳实践。
way that our company operates with best Git practices.
既然我已经完成了这三个区的提交，
Now that I finished committing across all three of these,
可以回到
I can now go back to my
主分支进行合并了。
main branch and merge some things in.
我关闭这些终端
So I'm going to close these terminal
环境，回到主终端。
environments and hop back to our main one.
现在我要求 Claude...
So now I'm going to ask Claude...
使用 git merge 命令
To use the Git merge command
合并 .trees 文件夹中的所有 worktrees
to merge in all of the worktrees in the .trees folder
并修复可能存在的任何冲突。
and fix any conflicts if there are any.
让 Claude Code 合并这些特定的 trees
So let's have Claude Code merge all of these particular trees
并确保它们按预期工作。
and make sure that they work as expected.
可以看到有三个可用的 worktrees。
We can see here there are three worktrees available.
我们开始逐一合并。
So we're going to start by merging in each of these worktrees.
确认这是我们想用的命令，
We'll confirm this is the command we want to use,
然后这应该会按预期工作。
and then this should work as expected.
看来测试功能部分没有冲突。
Looks like our testing feature doesn't have any conflicts.
接着合并 UI 功能。
Let's bring on our UI feature.
同样，我们可以自己写命令，
And again, we could write these commands on our own,
但 Claude Code 知道该怎么做。
but Claude Code knows exactly what to do from our prompt.
现在合并质量功能分支。
Now we can merge in the quality feature branch.
在这里我们会看到是否有冲突。
And here we'll see if there are any conflicts.
如你所见，在该特定文件中存在冲突。
and as we can see, in this particular file, there are conflicts.
我们将让 Claude Code
So what we're going to have Claude Code do
分析冲突并完成合并。
is analyze these conflicts and complete the merge.
当你不想手动处理细小合并冲突时，
This can be quite valuable when you have small merge conflicts
这非常有用。
that you don't want to manually go through each time.
拥有测试也非常有价值，
Having tests here is also quite valuable
确保合并完成后运行测试，
to make sure that once we've finished, we could
代码库仍能按预期工作。
run our tests and the code base works as expected.
现在正按预期继续合并，
It's now continuing with the merge as expected.
并提交所有
and it's going to commit all of
已解决冲突的更改。
these changes with the resolved merge conflicts.
如果愿意，我之后可以让它
If I'd like after, I can ask for it to remove
移除这些 worktrees。
these worktrees or I can keep them there if I need.
我做一个快速测试，
So I'll do a quick test to
确保文件都在，
make sure that these files are here
且合并配置
as expected and that the merge configurations
也符合预期。
are what are expected here as well.
我们也可以回到浏览器
We can also head back to the browser and
看看前端更改是否生效。
see if our front end changes are implemented as expected.
Claude Code 已经完成了：添加了依赖、
Looks like Claude Code has finished up, we've added necessary dependencies,
修改了 pyproject.toml、
we've modified our pyproject.toml
添加了测试、
We've added tests.
实现了深浅色主题。
we've implemented the light dark themes.
我们还实现了 Black 格式化工具，
We've implemented our black code formatter
确保代码符合特定格式，
to make sure that code is as expected in a certain format.
并将配置添加到了另一个工作树
and added that configuration in the same file
处理过的同一个文件中。
that we worked on with another work tree.
我们修复了所有冲突。
We fixed up any conflicts.
确保一切运行
Let's make sure this is working
正常。回到浏览器，
as expected. So back in the browser,
看到了这个漂亮的主题，
I now see here, I have this lovely theme
当我点击切换时，
and as I toggle through, I can
可以看到浅色和深色模式。
see a light theme and a dark theme.
虽然可能还有一些细节
So there might be some more things
需要调整，
I want to tweak here and there,
但我已经能够跨技术栈的所有部分进行编辑，
but I've been able to edit across all parts of the stack,
甚至处理了 Linting 和 DevOps 工作，
even do things in the linting and DevOps side of things,
而这一切都没有发生覆盖
all without overwriting,
或产生头疼的冲突——全靠 Git worktrees 的力量。
causing challenging headaches through the power of Git worktrees.
在下一课中，我们将看到如何
In the next lesson, we're going to see how
在终端之外
we can use Claude Code outside of the terminal
通过 GitHub 集成来审查 PR、
through an integration with GitHub to allow for reviewing pull requests,
进行更改并在终端生态系统之外提供帮助。
making changes and being helpful outside of the terminal ecosystem.